The End of the Sea Did you know there's an
awesome treasure hidden
at the end of the sea?
And anyone who finds it,
the King of the Pirates!
Is that exciting or what?
There are incredible adventures
out there just waiting for us!
Bon voyage.
Have the courage that sail and believe!
And we will see.
A glimpse of the sun rising?
On our tomorrow.
Back when we first started.
We had separate horizons.
Sailed toward different dreams.
Things have changed now!
For together we found.
We look through the spyglass and see.
And we know that our hearts
have brought us here.
Where the conscious points our destiny.
There's no looking back,
take the hell with me!
Bon voyage, we can't
stop all our troubles.
Forget the past.
Though the future's
unclear, we still can smile.
We know we'll get there!
No regrets.
Every tear that we've cried only helps.
Our dreams come true.
You and those dreams
are precious in my life.
A glimpse of the sun
rising on our tomorrow?
Uh, do you mind if I call you, Issie?
Can you really tell which way the
gravity blue rider's ship is heading?
Yeah, that's amazing.
Even from this far away, you can hear the
sound of their voices inside the forest.
But are you sure you're feeling all right?
You've been trembling ever
since we picked you up.
It's just, it's just that I've
never ever been this afraid before.
Everyone's voices, everyone's
voices keep disappearing one by one.
Yes, I'm sorry, we've got to hurry, Conis.
Yes, father.
I'm finally a pirate.
I think instead of looking for the
others, I'll just look for the gold.
That was your shock, everybody.
That place over there seems like
a good spot for gold to hide.
Who knows?
Maybe the others will end up there, too.
Hold on!
Where do you think you're going?
I'm sorry, but I've got to locate Enero.
You can't leave a lady.
I'm a lone way out here.
I already said I was sorry.
I don't have time to
explain my suspicions,
but I fear that my men's
lives may be in great danger.
No, this whole land may be in danger.
Pierre, can you fly? Pierre!
That's all?
Hold it right there, you heartless brute!
How could you?
And you call yourself a god!
Get back here!
Think this over!
I guess the main thing now would be
to give these guys some first aid.
You guys are still alive, aren't you?
Oh, Chopper, hurry up and get back here!
Ah! What? What?
Hazel!
Thomas?
And her dad?
Dad, what are you doing here?
And would you knock it off
with that horn already?
Let me go!
Wait, no, you mustn't go. Let go!
You can't go into the forest.
You'll be killed.
I promise we'll only
stay for a little while.
I said let go!
Oh, this young lady is Issie.
Stand back, you blue sea
devil, or I'll smash you!
I'm a brave warrior of Shandora!
That's nice, kid.
You want to fight me?
Have a face full of impact.
This is terrible.
They've been burnt black.
They need first aid at once.
At any rate, I'm sorry.
Now, quick, turn your ship
up the path we just came on.
We used a milky dial
to create a new river.
If you follow it, you can exit
directly to the White White Sea.
Quick, before the enemy
realizes we're here.
Then shouldn't you have been
a little quieter getting here?
Oh, by the way, I almost forgot
I brought something to give you.
Thank you.
What?
Or were you still here?
I'm sorry.
I guess I must have dozed off.
Is something wrong?
You seem to be in pain
I've kept my promise, haven't I?
I haven't moved a muscle.
I can't.
Beat you, can I?
No, you can't.
Do you understand now?
I am living lightning.
Try as you might, no mere man
can defeat such divine power.
Surely as a native of the sky you've seen
it flashing in the distance, haven't you?
Since ancient times,
men have trembled before the unknown forces
of nature and worshipped them as God.
Anything the fools could not understand
reduced them to abject terror.
No matter what happens to mankind,
whether for good or for evil,
it is said to be the work of God.
It's inevitable.
Mankind accepts that it can never
defeat the disasters of nature.
I'm one of them.
Ahhhh!
Oh, a breath dialing.
Bird blade!
I have to tell Wiper, we
can't win this battle.
This is suicide.
Even if he sacrifices himself,
the reject won't work.
It's too late to run now.
We've got to fall back and regroup.
Or else...
or else...
Did you think that you could
move faster than lightning?
Your five minutes are up.
And now it's my turn.
One million volt body.
WIPER!
Did you hear that?
What? What's happening?
What's wrong?
Aisa?
The voices!
They're disappearing!
Damn, I guess my electricity
traveled down the Milky Road.
Another 20 voices vanished
after that lightning bolt.
The stupid fools.
On the upper yard, 81 people
began the survival game.
Two hours have passed, and of that
eighty-one, fifty-six have fallen.
Thirteen of my divine squad still remain.
Five members of the Straw
Hat crew are still with us.
And seven warriors of Shandora.
That means there are twenty-five
players still in the game.
That's a lot more survivors
than I predicted there would be.
No matter.
They'll all fall in their
turn, one right after another.
The only real question remaining
is, who will come with me?
It's amazing!
You're incredible, Nami!
She's all yours now and as good as new!
Yeah, thanks!
I don't know what you did, but I love it!
This thing is so fast, it's crazy!
It's true.
And jet dials went extinct
hundreds of years ago.
It's really quite astonishing.
Imagine how shocked I was to find
one aboard the Waver you left.
I fear we're running out of
things to occupy ourselves with.
We had planned to lead all
of you to the end of Skypiea,
but it seems our
circumstances have changed.
I guess the best thing
to do is get the ship
to the coast where we all agreed to meet.
There's really no reason to worry.
I'm sure they're fine.
You know, when the four of
those goofballs get together,
there's practically no stopping them.
There aren't any four-man groups.
At the most, there's maybe two.
If there were a four-man group on the
island, I'd know about it, and I don't.
It's Mantara.
That's the power that Eneru
and his priests use, huh?
I was born able to use it.
That's why...
that's why I'm so afraid.
You have no idea how scary it
is to hear voices disappear.
You're not crying again, are you?
No, I'm not crying, you
stupid blue sea person!
Her waiver had broken down.
Luckily, our boat happened to pass by.
If we hadn't gotten to her when we did,
she would have been eaten by a sky shark.
What were you thinking
coming out here by yourself?
I don't know, but I couldn't keep
sitting around doing nothing.
Lucky, and everybody.
I hope everyone is all right.
Ugh, what a day.
This is crappy.
I'm starving and I left my
bag outside this stupid cave.
And all the fruit trees
around here are rotten.
And all I can think about is eating
that yummy breakfast Sanji made.
What kind of messed up cave
did I wind up in anyway?
Can't seem to find an exit anywhere.
I wonder if everybody's already
made it to this city of gold.
I bet it's all pretty and
shiny and golden and stuff.
And they probably make all
kinds of good food there too.
I can't wait to get there and find out.
I guess I could've been walking forever.
I think I'll have that lunch now.
Who's there?
Sorry, fellow, but I don't speak bird.
If it's my food you're after,
hey, you're not getting it.
Stop staring at me.
Would you stop following me?
Listen, feather brain,
I just ate all my food.
I don't have any more, okay?
Besides, I wouldn't give
you any even if I had some,
so get lost before I lose my temper.
What is your problem anyhow?
Walking all weird with your big fat
melon head face in the wrong direction.
I don't want to have to
fight you, bird, but I will.
Got it?
In three hours, a mere five of the 81
people on this island will be left standing.
There's only one hour
left until my proclaimed
time is up And 25
survivors currently remain.
This can't be.
What's Inaru doing here?
He's going down.
And now, 24.
Well, it seems all your
talk doesn't amount to much.
Domain Madagascar!
A runic statue.
Ben-Dempleur, commis-je-la.
How long are you going to insist
on protecting this withered,
good-for-nothing-hold-city?
Indefinitely.
Why must you disrespect what our
ancestors had held so sacred?
The past has nothing to do
with me, so why should I care?
That doesn't surprise me.
Only the foolish say such things.
How dare you insult someone so powerful!
Super Punch Mountain!
I've got to get away
from these ruins before
this simpleton destroys
what's left of them!
I chose to travel with Luffy.
But these ruins could hold
the clues to an unspoken
history that's been
lost to the world below?
How long do you plan on running?
I don't understand it.
You finally decided to face me?
Yes.
It's too late for you.
Too late?
Even if you choose to
repent, I won't forgive you.
Oh, you won't forgive me, I see.
All because of these
shabby old ruins you adore.
A pile of rubble that
doesn't even belong to you.
That's right.
Those ruins don't belong to anyone.
I've grown tired of this, and
I'm tired of talking to you.
Well, not to worry.
In just a few short
moments you won't have to
talk to me ever again
because unfortunately,
you're going to be crushed
to death underneath me!
Rock Mountain!
I can unleash all of my
power on you in this place!
All you do is charge
around like a clumsy bull!
With no regard for the weight of
the history that you've destroyed!
Hang!
This body's too heavy.
I'll jump you to ribbons!
That's Hadex Mountain!
My eyes!
I can't see!
What are you doing?
Why did you turn the
dials around backwards?
You're going to kill me!
What you have carelessly destroyed
were priceless treasures,
relics so rare it would
be next to impossible?
to measure their actual worth.
It's true that history may repeat
itself, but people can't go back in time.
A stupid brute like you
wouldn't understand that.
I understand.
Please, please, I'm sorry.
Won't you forgive me?
That's out of the question.
Well, in that case, I'll have
to kill you, then won't I?
Ahh! My fingers! My fingers!
Snow blue!
Delphinium!
No! No!
I'm afraid it's far too late for that.
Clutch!
That was certainly unpleasant.
This should be the center of the city.
But it doesn't match up at all
with the map on the monitor.
The monitor of the entire city was
broken up and it was thrust into the sky.
It's so strange.
Could this really be the City of Gold?
The size and the topography
are all completely different.
And what's most unnatural of all...
The only entrance is at the top.
Could it be?
I think I can go below.
It's so vast.
The ruins really do go much deeper.
I thought it was bizarre that all these
blue sea ruins had island clouds for ground.
The ruins above are nothing more
than the upper parts of the city,
eaten up by island clouds.
There's still more below.
Light! Light!
It's all so incredible.
The ancient city collapsed 800 years ago,
but I can hardly believe
it's been that long.
It's still so majestic and grand.
I've actually found it.
This really is the great
Shandora, a city of gold.
It can't be!
So then,
you're saying that it's possible our
lost history could actually be uncovered?
And the Poneglyphs are the key
to unlocking these records?
The ancient Poneglyph symbols, so the
Shendorians were familiar with them.
But only the ones who made the
Poneglyphs were able to read them.
We shall know the true meaning
and utter it to no one.
It's our legacy to be the
inheritors of history,
with the sounding of the Grand Belfry.
That's right.
I remember Nolan's old logbook
mentioning a giant gold bell being here.
But if that's true, where could it be?
All of the city's ancient
writings were burned in a fire.
The entire history of
this place was eradicated.
They'll all manage somehow, right?
They've come through this
kind of stuff before.
Quit following me!
Sure goes down a long way.
A poneglyph was carried into the city.
There's no question about it.
The city faced great hostility.
Shandora, the mystical city of gold,
fought and fell to protect that poneglyph.
And that means the Grand Belfry located
in the center of the Four Altars.
It could contain the
text of the true history.
It could be the real poneglyph.